Register to The Benny Goodman Papers
Yale University Music Library
The Benny Goodman Papers
1910-1992
MSS 53
Yale University Music Library
106
(129 boxes)
Musical arrangements, correspondence and other papers, photographs, and additional materials relating to Benny Goodman (1909-1986), the clarinetist and band leader. At present, this register consist of scores and/or parts to musical arrangements written for Goodman's band, as well as some sound recordings. Unprocessed materials in the Papers include: photographs; programs and scrapbooks; additional sound recordings; film reels and miscellaneous items.
Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986
Basie, Count, 1904-1984
Bunch, John, 1921-2010
Burns, Ralph, 1922-2001
Clayton, Buck, 1911-1991
Cohn, Al, 1925-1988
Edwards, Teddy, 1924-2003
Ellington, Duke, 1899-1974
Evans, Gil, 1912-1988
Feller, Sid, 1916-2006
Gutesha, Mladen
Henderson, Fletcher, 1897-1952
Henderson, Horace, 1904-1988
Hensel, Wes, 1917-1982
Jenkins, Gordon, 1910-1984
Karlin, Fred
Kincaide, Deane
Lipman, Joe, 1915-2007
Mancini, Henry, 1924-1994
Miller, Glenn, 1904-1944
Mundy, Jimmy, 1907-1983
Murphy, Lyle, 1908-2005
Newsom, Tommy
O'Farrill, Chico, 1921-2001
Ogermann, Claus, 1930-
Powell, Mel, 1923-1998
Sampson, Edgar, 1907-1973
Sauter, Eddie, 1914-1981
Stegmeyer, Bill, 1916-1968
Templeton, Alec, 1910-1963
Thompson, Johnny
Todd, Tommy
Wilder, Alec, 1907-1980
Williams, George, 1917-
Williams, Mary Lou, 1910-1981
Woode, William Henri, 1909-1994
Conditions Governing Access
The Papers are open to qualified researchers by appointment. There are no restricted materials in the collection. Please contact the Special Collections staff to schedule an appointment. Some of the materials may be stored at the Library's off-campus shelving facility, so researchers should allow at least two business days to have the appropriate boxes paged.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
The Benny Goodman Papers were established in the Music Library of Yale University by Benny Goodman in 1986.
Arrangement
In 9 series as follows: I. Music II. Correspondence. III. Photographs. IV. Scrapbooks. V. Programs and Publicity. VI. Scripts, Interviews, and Articles. VII. Financial and Legal. VIII. Awards, Honors, and Academic Regalia. IX. Miscellaneous.
Scope and Contents
This register currently describes scores and/or parts to musical arrangements written for Benny Goodman's bands, orchestras, and combos. Some sound recordings are also included. The Papers also include published music in Goodman's collection; correspondence (including letters from many prominent musicians and political figures); photographs; scrapbooks; concert programs and publicity materials; scripts, interviews, and articles; financial and legal documents; awards, honors, and academic regalia; additional sound recoridings and film reels; and miscellaneous other items. Descriptions of these materials will be added to the register at a later date.
Biographical / Historical
Benny Goodman was born in Chicago, May 30, 1909. He received his first musical training at a local synagogue, and later studied clarinet with Franz Schoepp. Goodman made his debut at the age of twelve, and left home to become a full-time professional clarinetist when he was sixteen.
After a decade of performing as a free-lancer and as a member of Ben Pollak's band, Goodman established his first big band in 1934, and soon it achieved unprecedented success. He won great acclaim both for his dazzling clarinet solos and for the brilliance of his band. In an era of segregation, Goodman was a pioneer in hiring without regard to race; his ensemble included outstanding black musicians (such as Teddy Wilson) as well as leading white performers (such as Gene Krupa). Goodman also employed talented arrangers, including Fletcher Henderson, Eddie Sauter, and many others. At his peak, in the late 1930s, Goodman may have been the most popular musician in the world. His Carnegie Hall concert on January 16, 1938 is regarded as a key moment in jazz history.
Goodman did not restrict himself to big band music; he also won renown for his work with a series of small combos that included Wilson, Krupa, Lionel Hampton, Charlie Christian, and other prominent jazz musicians. He even pursued a classical career, performing clarinet concertos with numerous orchestras and playing chamber music with ensembles such as the Budapest String Quartet. He commissioned major works from Bela Bart'k, Aaron Copland, Paul Hindemith, and other composers.Although the swing era eventually passed, Goodman retained a large and loyal following, even as bop, rock, and other musical styles came into vogue. He and his band performed widely, not only in the United States, but also in Latin America, Europe, the Soviet Union, and East Asia. Over the course of his long career, Goodman made innumerable recordings and appeared frequently on radio, television, and film. His life and music have been the subject of many biographies, discographies, and other studies.
Benny Goodman died in New York on June 13, 1986. Years after his passing, he remains the unchallenged 'King of Swing.'
Big band music -- Scores and parts; Clarinet with dance orchestra -- Scores and parts; Clarinet with jazz ensemble -- Scores and parts; Dance orchestra music -- Scores and parts; Jazz; Music -- United States -- 20th Century; Goodman, Benny, 1909-1986
- Band and Combo Arrangements
  - ABSENCE MAKES THE HEART GROW FONDER Henderson, Fletcher, 1939 (Box 01, Folder 01)
    General
    BG No.: C117/136/30
    Score: yes
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
    Key: A
    Drum part a recopy. Complete.
  - ABSENT MINDED MOON Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 01, Folder 02)
    BG No.: A58
    Parts: none
    Key: E flat
  - AC-DC CURRENT, c.1958 (Box 01, Folder 03)
    BG No.: A143
    Score: no
    Parts: cl/tpt/PGBD
    Key: G
    "Head arrangement" notated by Bob Wilbur.
  - AFRAID TO SAY HELLO Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 01, Folder 04)
    BG No.: A230
    Key: C
  - AFTER DARK Henderson, Horace, 1936 (Box 01, Folder 05)
    BG No.: A206/10
  - AFTER GLOW Murphy, Spud, 7/14/1936 (Box 01, Folder 06)
    BG No.: A207/387/40
    Key: E
  - AFTER I SAY I'M SORRY Henderson, Fletcher, c.1945 (Box 01, Folder 07)
    BG No.: B70/A2/142
    Parts: cl(3)/saxAATTB(2)/tpt1-3/tbn1-3(2)4/PGBD
    Tbn4 part marked "optional".
  - AFTER I SAY I'M SORRY (Box 01, Folder 08)
    BG No.: none
    Parts: rhythm lead sheet (3)
    Key: B flat
  - AFTER YOU'RE GONE Henderson, Fletcher (Box 01, Folder 8A)
    BG No.: A3/36/179
    Parts: saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
    Key: G flat
    These parts are collected from various different copies to form a playable set.
  - AH MEN!-AH WOMEN!/QUINTET MEDLEY Burns, Ralph (Box 34, Folder 07)
    See: Swing Into Spring 1959.
  - AIN'T MISBEHAVIN' Karlin, Fred, 5/26/1960 (Box 01, Folder 09)
    BG No.: D311/104
    Parts: saxAT/tpt/tbn/PGBDV
    Key: A flat
  - AIN'T SHE PRETTY Henderson, Fletcher (Box 01, Folder 10)
    Score: photocopy
  - AIR MAIL SPECIAL Bunch, John, 1960 (Box 01, Folder 11)
    BG No.: G124
    Parts: P
  - AIRMAIL SPECIAL Mundy, Jimmy, 1941 (Box 01, Folder 12)
    BG No.: C344/188
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
    Condensed sax and brass arrangement by Deanne Kincaide. Complete.
  - ALADDIN'S VAMP Newsom, Tommy, 1964 (Box 1A, Folder 13)
    BG No.: F111
    Parts: cl(2)/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
    Key: F
    One clarinet part marked "booth". Complete.
  - ALICE BLUE GOWN (Box 1A, Folder 14)
    BG No.: A201/333
    Key: D flat
  - ALL I NEED IS YOU Matthews, Dave, 1942 (Box 1A, Folder 15)
    BG No.: B232
  - ALL MY LIFE Henderson, Fletcher, 1936 (Box 1A, Folder 16)
    BG No.: C13/33/A59
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBD
    A flat introduction is taped over original in B flat. Brass have separate parts for each key. B flat version only: saxB/tpt4/tbn3.
  - ALL THE GIRLS Mundy, Jimmy, 1937 (Box 1A, Folder 17)
    BG No.: A250/119
  - ALL THE THINGS YOU ARE Sauter, Eddie, 1940 (Box 1A, Folder 18)
    BG No.: B204
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PBD
  - ALL THE THINGS YOU ARE Sauter, Eddie, 1940 (Box 1A, Folder 19)
    BG No.: B204/3A
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGB
  - ALL THE THINGS YOU ARE Sauter, Eddie, 1940 (Box 1A, Folder 20)
    BG No.: B204/304
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
    Renumbered and recopied. Complete.
  - ALL THE WAY CHOO CHOO O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 1B, Folder 21)
    BG No.: A203
    Arrangement of "Egghead" on reverse side of pages 1-3.
  - ALL THROUGH THE NITE Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 1B, Folder 22)
    BG No.: B231
  - ALLAH'S HOLIDAY Henderson, Fletcher, 1940 (Box 1B, Folder 23)
    BG No.: B128/C302/325
    Parts: cl/saxATT(-A2)/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
  - ALONE AT A TABLE FOR TWO Murphy, Spud, 1936 (Box 1B, Folder 24)
    BG No.: A202
  - ALONE TOGETHER (Box 1B, Folder 25)
    Key: D minor
  - ALWAYS Henderson, Horace, 1935 (Box 1B, Folder 26)
    BG No.: A356/A5
    Score and parts are recopies. Complete.
  - AM I BLUE Henderson, Fletcher, 1934 (Box 1B, Folder 27)
    BG No.: C221/110
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/GB
    Tbn1, G and B are newly copied; all others are original.
  - AM I BLUE Henderson, Fletcher, c.1946 (Box 1B, Folder 28)
    BG No.: A357
    Revoiced and expanded version by Fletcher Henderson.
  - AM I BLUE Henderson, Fletcher (Box 1B, Folder 28A)
    BG No.: 21
    Recopy.
  - AM I GONNA HAVE TROUBLE WITH YOU? Henderson, Horace, 1935 (Box 1C, Folder 29)
    BG No.: A204/11/26
    Parts: tbn2
  - AND THE ANGELS SING, 1939 (Box 1C, Folder 30)
    BG No.: A274/Al
    See also "Frahlich in Swing".
  - AND THE ANGELS SING (Box 1C, Folder 31)
    BG No.: A274
    Score: for five brass only
    1953 brass revoicing by Bill Fontaine for 1939 arrangement.
  - AND THE ANGELS SING O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 1C, Folder 32)
    BG No.: A274/163
    Key: A flat Complete.
  - AND THE ANGELS SING O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 1C, Folder 33)
    BG No.: A274/224
    Score: intro to revised arrangement only
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-4/PGBD
    Transposed from A flat version with new intro. See other O'Farrill arrangement for full score. Complete.
  - AND THE ANGELS SING (Box 1C, Folder 34)
    Parts: al/saxAATTB/tpt1-2(2)3(2)4/tbn1-3/PGBD
    1939 arrangement revised and transposed in 1985 by Sy Johnson.
  - AND THE ANGELS SING (Box 1D, Folder 35)
    BG No.: A274/88
    1939 arrangement transposed in 1946.
  - ANGELS CAME THRU, THE Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 1D, Folder 36)
    BG No.: B247
  - ANNUNCIACION, LA Ogerman, Claus, 1969 (Box 1D, Folder 37)
    BG No.: G5/L1
    Parts: cl(3)/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PG1-2BD
    Key: D
    Complete.
  - ANY PLACE I HANG MY HAT IS HOME Evans, Gil, 1956 (Box 1D, Folder 38)
    BG No.: B94/A6
  - ANYTHING Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 1D, Folder 39)
    BG No.: B129/C203/96A
    Parts: saxTB(-T1)/tpt1/tbn1-2/GBD
  - ANYTHING CAN SWING Mundy, Jimmy, 1937 (Box 1D, Folder 40)
    BG No.: B41
    Score: intro only
  - ANYTHING GOES Murphy, Spud, 1934 (Box 1D, Folder 41)
    BG No.: A8
    Cl, B and D parts are recopied.
  - APRIL IN MY HEART Henderson, Horace, 1938 (Box 02, Folder 01)
    BG No.: A154/744
  - APRIL IN MY HEART Woode, Henri, 1938 (Box 02, Folder 02)
    BG No.: B107
  - AQUARIUS Levinsky, Walt, 1969 (Box 02, Folder 03)
    BG No.: G10/A9
  - AQUARIUS-SUNSHINE Newsom, Tommy, 7/1969 (Box 02, Folder 04)
    Parts: cl/saxT/tpt/tbn/PGBD
  - AS LONG AS I LIVE Stegmeyer, Bill, 6/1960 (Box 02, Folder 05)
    BG No.: D232/51
    Parts: cl/saxAT/tpt/tbn/PGBDV
  - AS LONG AS WE STILL BELIEVE Wilder, Alec, 1945 (Box 02, Folder 06)
    BG No.: A205
  - AS SWEET AS YOU White, Johnny, 1946 (Box 02, Folder 07)
    BG No.: C240/28
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1,3-4/tbn1-2/PGBD/horn
  - ASHES TO ASHES Karlin, Fred, 10/6/1959 (Box 2A, Folder 08)
    BG No.: D62/9
  - AT THE DARKTOWN STRUTTER'S BALL Powell, Mel, 1942 (Box 2A, Folder 09)
    BG No.: A352/770
  - AT THE DARKTOWN STRUTTER'S BALL Murphy, Spud, 1934 (Box 2A, Folder 10)
    BG No.: A352/39/27
    Score expanded by Bill Fontaine; not original. Complete.
  - AT THE JAZZ BAND BALL Kincaide, Deane, 1946 (Box 2A, Folder 11)
    BG No.: B110
  - AUTUMN NOCTURNE Gutesha, Bobby, 1958 (Box 2A, Folder 12)
    BG No.: D50/227
  - BABY IT'S COLD OUTSIDE O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 2A, Folder 14)
    BG No.: B111/225
    Vocal arrangement.
  - BABY IT'S COLD OUTSIDE O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 2A, Folder 13)
    BG No.: C316
    Parts: saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGB
    Same as other O'Farill arrangement, only transposed. SaxA1 missing "encore".
  - BACH GOES TO TOWN Karlin, Fred, 10-11/1959 (Box 2B, Folder 15)
    BG No.: D223/10
    SaxA is flute throughout. Score includes 2 inserts indicating alterations. Included is a full set of photocopies. Complete.
  - BACH GOES TO TOWN Brant, Henry (Box 2B, Folder 15A)
    BG No.: B1
    Parts: cl(2)/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/B
    All parts are photocopies. Complete.
  - BACH GOES TO TOWN/FUGUE IN SWING Brant, Henry (Box 2B, Folder 15B)
    BG No.: 39
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/BD
    All saxes double on clarinet. Includes separate parts for cl1-5 for "Bach Goes to Town".
  - BACK IN YOUR OWN BACKYARD Karlin, Fred, 5/10/1960 (Box 2B, Folder 16)
    BG No.: D304/36
  - BAIA (Box 2B, Folder 17)
    BG No.: 74A
  - BALKAN-GRILL Gutesha, Bobby, 1958 (Box 2C, Folder 18)
    BG No.: G38/230
    Key: C minor
  - BALLAD FOR BENNY Nelson, Oliver, 1962 (Box 2C, Folder 19)
    BG No.: D419/265
  - BALLAD IN BLUE Murphy, Spud, 5/16/1935 (Box 2C, Folder 20)
    BG No.: D10/112
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/P(2)B
    Clarinet part is a recopy.
  - BALLAD IN BLUE Murphy, Spud (Box 2C, Folder 20A)
    BG No.: 29
    Recopy. All saxes double clarinet.
  - BALLET EPISODES Powell, Mel, 1947 (Box 2C, Folder 21)
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PBD
    Key: A minor
  - BALTIMORE ORIOLE Thompson, Johnny, 1942 (Box 2C, Folder 22)
    BG No.: C342/87A
    Parts: tpt1-2/tbn2/P
  - BASIN STREET BLUES Karlin, Fred, 6/10/1960 (Box 2C, Folder 23)
    BG No.: D314/406
  - BASIN STREET BLUES Karlin, Fred, 6/9/1960 (Box 2C, Folder 24)
    Includes sketch for score alterations.
  - BASIN STREET BLUES Jenkins, Gordon, 4-5/1976 (Box 2C, Folder 25)
    BG No.: G150
    All sax parts double flute or clarinet.
  - BASIN STREET BLUES Miller, Glenn, 1935 (Box 2D, Folder 26)
    BG No.: A48/69
    Tpt3, D parts are recopies.
  - BASIN STREET BLUES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 2D, Folder 27)
    BG No.: A48/51/596
    Score: original and photocopy
  - BEACHWOOD DRIVE Clayton, Buck, 1945 (Box 2D, Folder 28)
    BG No.: B112
  - BEAUTIFUL BABY (Box 2D, Folder 29)
    BG No.: A79/76
    Parts: cl/saxAAT/tpt1-2/tbn1/PG
  - BEER BARREL POLKA, 1939 (Box 2D, Folder 30)
    BG No.: C156/141
  - BEETLE, THE O'Farrill, Chico, 1949 (Box 2D, Folder 31)
    BG No.: A289
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBD/vocal quintet
  - BEGIN THE BEGUINE Henderson, Fletcher, 1939 (Box 2D, Folder 32)
    BG No.: C303/90
    Parts: cl/saxATB(-A2)/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PG(2)BD
    Extra guitar part does not match arrangement.
  - BEHAVE YOURSELF Henderson, Fletcher, 1947 (Box 2D, Folder 33)
    BG No.: A73
    Key: G minor
  - BEHAVE YOURSELF Burns, Ralph, 1947 (Box 2E, Folder 34)
  - BEI MIR BIST DU SCHON Hood, Bill, 6/1961 (Box 2E, Folder 35)
    BG No.: D415/21
  - BEI MIR BIST DU SCHON Williams, George, 1958 (Box 2E, Folder 36)
    BG No.: A361
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBD/vocal
  - BEI MIR BIST DU SCHON Mundy, Jimmy, 1938 (Box 2E, Folder 37)
    BG No.: A361/21
  - BENNY GOODMAN ANTHOLOGY: FUNERAL PARADE Prince, Bob, 5/1962 (Box 03, Folder 01)
    BG No.: D436/275
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBperc
    Key: F minor
    Complete
  - BENNY GOODMAN MEDLEY Abene, Mike, 1978 (Box 3A, Folder 02)
    BG No.: G35
    Medley: "Don't Be That Way", "Stompin' at the Savoy", "And the Angels Sing", "Why Don't You Do Right", "String of Pearls".
  - BENNY GOODMAN REVIEW, 1949 (Box 3B, Folder 03)
    BG No.: E2
    Parts: saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/B
  - BENNY TO HELEN (Box 3B, Folder 04)
    BG No.: C243/35A
    Parts: saxAAT/tpt1/tbn2-3/PGB
  - BENNY'S BAND Sauter, Eddie, 1940 (Box 3B, Folder 05)
    BG No.: A219/C323
    Parts: saxAATB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
  - BENNY'S BUGLE Martin, Skip, 1941 (Box 3C, Folder 06)
    BG No.: A360/54A
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGD
  - BERGEN BLUES Lieb, Dick (Box 3C, Folder 07)
    BG No.: Gg
  - BEST THINGS IN LIFE ARE FREE, THE Todd, Tommy, 1947 (Box 3C, Folder 08)
    BG No.: A103
  - BETWEEN THE DEVIL AND THE DEEP BLUE SEA Prince, Bob, 5/1962 (Box 3C, Folder 09)
    BG No.: 312/F23
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBDV
  - BETWEEN THE DEVIL AND THE DEEP BLUE SEA Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 3C, Folder 10)
    BG No.: 16
    Transcribed by Sy Johnson 9/1985 for PBS television special. Sax B/tpt4/tbn3 parts are marked "optional". Complete.
  - BETWEEN THE DEVIL AND THE DEEP BLUE SEA Wootten, Red, 1959 (Box 3D, Folder 11)
    BG No.: C216/24
    Parts: saxAT/tpt/tbn/PB
  - BETWEEN THE DEVIL AND THE DEEP BLUE SEA, 1959 (Box 3D, Folder 12)
    Score: sketch only
  - BIG CITY BEAT Edwards, Teddy, 8-9/1964 (Box 3D, Folder 13)
    BG No.: F128
  - BIG JOHN SPECIAL (Box 3D, Folder 13A)
    BG No.: 43/B3/G107
  - BILL BAILEY Karlin, Fred, 5/27/1960 (Box 3D, Folder 14)
    BG No.: D312/403
  - BILL BAILEY Lipman, Joe, 11/1961 (Box 3D, Folder 15)
    BG No.: D403/257
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBDV
  - BIRDS OF A FEATHER Henderson, Fletcher, 1941 (Box 3D, Folder 16)
    BG No.: B130/24A
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
  - BIRTH OF THE BLUES Sauter, Eddie, 1941 (Box 3E, Folder 17)
    BG No.: B131/10OA/C319
    Parts: cl/saxATTB(-A2)/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
  - BLACKBIRD Andre, Wayne, 1962 (Box 3E, Folder 18)
    Parts: cl/tpt/tbn/PGBD
  - BLACKBIRD Ogerman, Claus, 1969 (Box 3E, Folder 19)
    BG No.: G3/B4
    Parts: cl(3)/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
  - BLUE (AND BROKEN HEARTED) Henderson, Fletcher, 1947 (Box 3E, Folder 20)
    BG No.: A119/185
  - BLUE AND BROKEN HEARTED Jenkins, Gordon, 1935 (Box 3E, Folder 21)
    BG No.: A362/162/18
  - BLUE CLARINET Newsom, Tommy, 1964 (Box 3E, Folder 22)
    BG No.: F110
    Parts: cl(2)/saxT/tpt/tbn/PGBD
  - BLUE HAWAII Stegmeyer, Bill, 10/1962 (Box 3F, Folder 23)
    BG No.: D336/61
  - BLUE INTERLUDE Carter, Benny, 1938 (Box 3F, Folder 24)
    BG No.: A247/116/687
  - BLUE MONK McFarland, Gary, 1962 (Box 3F, Folder 25)
    BG No.: D432/289
  - BLUE PRELUDE Jenkins, Gordon, 4-5/1976 (Box 3F, Folder 26)
    BG No.: G137
    Parts: cl(2)/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-4/PGBD
    Photocopies only: cl/tpt3-4/tbn2-4/GB. Complete.
  - BLUE ROOM Henderson, Fletcher, 1938 (Box 3F, Folder 27)
    BG No.: B5/9
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PG(2)BD
    The G, B and D parts included with this set were used with the recopied arrangement which follows for performances in the 1980's.
  - BLUE ROOM Henderson, Fletcher, 1938 (Box 3F, Folder 27A)
    Parts: cl/saxATT(-A2)/tpt1-3/tbn1-2
    Recopy. Includes score and parts for saxB/tpt4/tbn3 added by Sy Johnson and marked "optional".
  - BLUE SKIES Hensel, Wes, 2/1961 (Box 04, Folder 01)
    BG No.: C310
    Parts: cl/saxAT/tpt/tbn/G
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 02)
    BG No.: 6
    Parts: tpt1/tbn1-2/PB
    Key: B minor
    Parts in Henderson's own hand.
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 03)
    BG No.: B6
    Parts: cl/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGB
    1949 recopy. Includes photocopies of: saxAATT/tptl-3/tbnl-2. SaxB marked 70A.
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 04)
    Parts: saxAATT/tpt1-2/tbn3/G
    1937 recopy.
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 05)
    BG No.: B6/C310
    Parts: saxB(3)/tPt3-4/tbn3/"rhythm"(3)D
    Misc. parts (1953-1969) usable together.
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 06)
    Score: for added brass and saxB only
    Parts: saxB/tbn3
    Parts added by Sy Johnson in 1985.
  - BLUE SKIES, 1946 (Box 04, Folder 07)
    BG No.: C50/31
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD/horn
    All parts (except saxT1,tpt2-3,tbn2) also have a 4 measure insert to be used as an intro to a vocal chorus in C minor.
  - BLUE SKIES Burns, Ralph (Box 33, Folder 13)
    See: Swing Into Spring 1958.
  - BLUE SKIES Henderson, Fletcher, 1935 (Box 04, Folder 6A)
    BG No.: 34/C310
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-4/tbn1-2/PGBD
    Cl and tpt parts marked "revised". These parts are collected from various copies to form a playable set. Some photocopies.
  - BLUES Hensel, Wes, 1961 (Box 04, Folder 08)
    BG No.: D413
    Parts: cl/saxAT/tpt/tbn
  - BLUES IN E FLAT WITH RELEASE Powell, Mel, 1948 (Box 04, Folder 09)
    BG No.: 125
    Parts: cl2/saxT/PB
    Also includes pencil draft of sax and vibes parts.
  - BLUES IN MY HEART Carter, Benny, 1934 (Box 04, Folder 10)
    BG No.: C322/84
    Parts: saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PBD/banjo
  - BLUES JUMPED UP AND GOT ME, THE Henderson, Fletcher, 1946 (Box 04, Folder 11)
    BG No.: A141
  - BLUES MEDLEY Williams, George (Box 33, Folder 08)
    See: Swing Into Spring 1958
  - BLUES VIEWS Wayne, Chuck, 1948 (Box 04, Folder 12)
    BG No.: 123
    Parts: PGD
  - BOAT LEAVING FOR NEW YORK Woode, Henri, 1936 (Box 04, Folder 12)
    BG No.: A213/20
  - BOEHM, LA Newsom, Tommy, 1964 (Box 4A, Folder 13)
    BG No.: L2/299/G24
    Also includes slightly different pencil copy of tbnl and pencil intro for bass.
  - BOLERO Henderson, Fletcher, 1939 (Box 4A, Folder 14)
    Parts: cl(2)/saxAATTB/tpt1-3/tbn1-3/PGBD
    Parts are from 1969 recopy.
  - BOLERO Henderson, Fletcher, 1939 (Box 4A, Folder 15)
    BG No.: B132/177/C304
    Parts: cl/saxATTB(-A1)/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PGBD
    Original parts. Final measures left unfinished.
  - BOLERO Szathmary, Irving, 1934 (Box 4A, Folder 16)
    BG No.: C304/244A
    Parts: cl/saxAAT/tpt1,3/tbn1-2/PBD
  - BOLERO, 1939 (Box 4A, Folder 17)
    BG No.: B132/177
    Sax doubles: Al-flute, A2-cl, T1-cl, and T2-bscl.
  - BOMBER'S MOON, A Thompson, Johnny, 1942 (Box 4A, Folder 18)
    BG No.: C209/120A
    Parts: saxABBs(-A2)/B
  - BOOGIE BLUES, 10/1959 (Box 4A, Folder 19)
    BG No.: D229/18
    Also includes sketch of piano part. Complete.
  - BOPPER OF SEVILLE, THE Villepigue, Paul, 3/29/1949 (Box 4A, Folder 20)
    BG No.: A290
  - BOTH SIDES NOW Ogerman, Claus, 1969 (Box 4A, Folder 21)
    BG No.: G36/B7
    Parts: cl(2)/saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/PGBD
  - BRAZIL Lipman, Joe, 11/4/1961 (Box 4B, Folder 22)
    BG No.: D402/260
  - BREAKFAST FEUD, 1959 (Box 4B, Folder 23)
    BG No.: B71/26
    Parts: cl(2)/saxT/tpt(2)/tbn/P(2)G(2)B(2)D(2)
    "Head arrangement" transcribed by Bob Wilbur in 1959.
  - BREAKIN' IN A PAIR OF SHOES Henderson, Fletcher, 1936 (Box 4B, Folder 24)
    BG No.: A63/A62/133
    Parts: cl/saxAATT/tpt1-3/tbn1-2/PG/tuba
  - BREEZE AND I, THE Sauter, Eddie, c.1940 (Box 4B, Folder 25)
    BG No.: B188
  - BROADWAY Childers, Buddy, 3/16/1961 (Box 4B, Folder 26)
    BG No.: C252
  - BROWSIN' AROUND Mundy, Jimmy, 1937 (Box 4B, Folder 27)
    BG No.: A347/214
  - BUCKLE DOWN WINSOCKI Jenkins, Cliff, 1941 (Box 4C, Folder 29)
    BG No.: 53A
    Parts: saxB/tpt1/PGBD
    These parts use pieces of an earlier copy, with revisions.
  - BUCKLE DOWN WINSOCKI Jenkins, Cliff, 1946 (Box 4B, Folder 28)
    BG No.: A147/113/C220
    Horn can be substituted for tbn3. This is a revision and expansion of 1941 arrangement. Complete.
  - BUDS WON'T BUD Henderson, Fletcher, 1941 (Box 4C, Folder 30)
    BG No.: A33/329
  - BUGLE CALL RAG Williams, George, 1958 (Box 4C, Folder 31)
    BG No.: B38/26
    Score: Yes
  - BUGLE CALL RAG Mundy, Jimmy, 1936 (Box 4C, Folder 32)
    BG No.: B38/BB
    Included are extra photocopies of: saxAATTB/tpt1-4/tbn1-3/G. The clarinet part is also a photocopy.
  - BUGLE CALL RAG (Box 4C, Folder 33)
    BG No.: B3B/175
  - BULGAR AND OTHER BALKAN TYPE INVENTIONS, THE Carisi, Johnny, 4/1962 (Box 05, Folder 01)
    BG No.: D426/293